

# Timo Kelder

#### PHD Hydroclimatology

Louahborouah, UK

■ t.kelder@lboro.ac.uk | 🏶 https://timokelder.netlify.app | 🖸 https://github.com/timokelder | 🛅

timo-kelder-960867120 | ¥ @timokelder

"Large ensemble simulations to quantify and explain climate extremes"

# Summary.

Timo Kelder is a PhD student in climate science at Loughborough University, with visiting status at Oxford University and ECMWF. Supervised by Professor Rob Wilby and Dr Tim Marjoribanks, he analyses big data from large-ensemble climate model simulations to improve precipitation design standards and to assess trends in extreme precipitation. As part of an MSc in Earth and Environment at Wageningen University, Timo held an internship at the Norwegian Meteorological Institute (MetNor). As hydrologist within the project 'Translating Weather Extremes into the Future' at MetNor, he was part of an integral team to tackle high-impact flood events in Norway.

# **Education**

### **Loughborough University**

Loughborough, UK Sep. 2018 - exp. Sep. 2021

РнD

· Large ensemble simulations to quantify and explain climate extremes.

#### **Wageningen University and Research**

Wageningen, The Netherlands

Aug. 2015 - exp. Feb. 2018

- MSc. Earth and Environment
- Internship: Hydrological impacts of atmospheric rivers under current and future climate. Graded: 8.
- Thesis: A simplified routing model for data scarce lowland catchments. Graded: 8.
- Courses: 8

#### **Wageningen University and Research**

Wageningen, The Netherlands

BSc. Soil, Water and Atmosphere

Sep. 2012 - Jul. 2015

• Thesis: Bedform height and length increase linearly with distance from the sea in a tidal environment: a pioneering study of the tidal zone of the Kapuas river. Graded: 8.

# Work Experience

## The Norwegian Meteorological Institute

Oslo, Norway

RESEARCHER

INTERN

Feb. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Dec. 2015 - Feb. 2016

• Simulating high-impact flood events in Norway as part of the TWEX project.

**Ecovision** Curação

• I applied the SWMM model to Curação to understand sediment transport in the rainwater drainage system of Curação.

# **Presentations**

EGU 2020 Online!

Presentor May 2020

Title

AGU 2018 Washington DC

PRESENTOR Dec 2018

Title

Still need to add others

PRESENTOR

APRIL 30, 2020 TIMO KELDER · RÉSUMÉ 1